重叠了一度
One degree to overlap.
准备拍照
Stand by to photograph.
拍照
Now.
3天来一直干这个，长官
Three days of this now, sir.
其他星舰肯定绘制过这里的部分星图
Other ships must have made star maps of some of this.
不可能，上尉，我们是第一个来到这么远的地方
Negative, lieutenant. We're the first to reach this far.
长官，有物体出现，正朝我们移动
Sir, contact with an object. It's moving toward us.
- 还无法显示影像 - 偏导仪，最高强度
- No visual contact yet. - Deflectors, full intensity.
- 它正以光速前进 - 碰撞航向
- It's coming at light speed. - Collision course.
闪避模式，苏鲁
Evasive maneuvers, Mr. Sulu.
目标也变换方向了，长官，继续朝我们飞来
Object changing direction too, sir. Keeps coming at us.
我无法获得它的信号，长官
I'm getting no signal from it, sir.
仍然是碰撞航向
Still collision course.
- 偏导仪没法让它停止 - 拉响警报
- Deflectors aren't stopping it. - Sound alarm.
- 它正在减速，史波克先生 - 取消警报
- It's slowing down, Mr. Spock. - Countermand alarm.
所有引擎，完全关闭
All engines, full stop.
视像联接
Visual contact.
慢速前进，绕道航行，苏鲁先生
Ahead slow. Steer a course around it, Mr. Sulu.
它挡住了我们
It's blocking the way.
不用喊起来，贝利先生
Quite unnecessary to raise your voice, Mr. Bailey.
停止所有引擎，拉响警报
All engines, stop. Sound the alert.
舰桥呼叫所有甲板，警戒状态
Bridge to all decks. Condition: Alert.
所有甲板，警戒状态
All decks, condition: Alert.
寇克舰长请到舰桥来
Captain Kirk to the Bridge.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
TLF荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：土豆爱 马田的心事 刘诗濛
校对：kmdangdangli 喜马拉雅 xjCGI
第一季第十集
科波麦特的考验
舰长日志，星历1512.2
Captain's log, stardate 1512.2:
在我们绘制星图的第三天，一个不明立方物体
On our third day of star mapping, an unexplained cubicle object
挡住了我船的去路
blocked our vessel's path.
舰桥上，史波克先生立即发布预警命令
On the Bridge, Mr. Spock immediately ordered general alert.
我当时正在医务室进行季度体检
My location, Sickbay. Quarterly physical check.
再来几秒钟
Just a few seconds more.
就几秒钟
早就不止了
I got more.
这才叫男子汉，继续，多流点汗
That's a boy. Keep it up. Work up a little sweat.
- 对你有好处 - 快累死我了
- It'll do you good. - You're killing me.
要累死我了
You're killing me.
停
Stop.
气喘吁吁了？
Winded?
我告诉你这将是最后一次
You'd be the last one I'd tell.
- 我是寇克，有什么情况？ - 看看这个，舰长
- Kirk here. What's going on? - Have a look at this, captain.
- 那是什么？ - 还不确定
- What's that? - Undetermined.
不管是什么，它挡着我们的路呢，我们动它就跟着动
Whatever it is, it's blocking our way. When we move, it moves as well.
- 某种飞船？ - 不像
- A vessel of some kind? - Negative.
更像是某种装置
More some type of device.
我很快上去
I'll be right up.
你看到警报灯一直闪，怎么不告诉我？
You could see the alarm lights flashing from there. Why didn't you tell me?
这样你才有机会完成体检，不是吗？
Finally finished a physical on you, didn't I?
我是什么，医生还是月球穿梭机的售票员？
What am I, a doctor or a moon-shuttle conductor?
如果每次灯一亮我就报告
If I jumped every time a light came on around here,
那我最终会疯掉的
I'd end up talking to myself.
所有甲板警戒
All decks: Alert.
舰桥
Bridge.
- 舰长呼叫舰桥 - 我是史波克
- Captain to Bridge. - Spock here.
- 有变化吗？ - 没有
- Any changes? - Negative.
不管是什么，看来它想把我们挡在这儿
Whatever it is, it seems to want to just hold us here.
- 有何危险迹象？ - 没有
- Any indication of danger from it? - Negative.
我先换下衣服，完毕
I'll change first then. Captain out.
所有甲板正常，贝利先生
All decks have reported green, Mr. Bailey.
- 是，长官 - 舰长来的时候
- Yes, sir. - And when the captain arrives,
- 他需要一份报告… - 立方体的相对距离和位置
- he'll expect a report... - The cube's range and position.
我会拿出报告的
I'll have it by then.
刚才提高音量并不是说我害怕了
Raising my voice back there doesn't mean I was scared
或者不能胜任我的工作了
or couldn't do my job.
只是人类肾上腺素变化的结果
It means I happen to have a human thing called an adrenaline gland.
但确实听起来很麻烦
It does sound most inconvenient, however.
你有考虑过切除它吗？
Have you considered having it removed?
有意思
Very funny.
想和史波克拼脑力，每次他都会把你切成小块的
Try to cross brains with Spock, he'll cut you to pieces every time.
- 舰长呼叫舰桥 - 我是史波克
- Captain to Bridge. - Spock here.
- 有生命迹象吗？ - 没有
- Any signs of life? - Negative.
- 试过所有的呼叫频率吗？ - 试过
- Have you tried hailing frequencies? - Affirmative.
立方体没反应
No answer from the cube.
通知各部门负责人到舰桥会合
Have the department heads meet on the Bridge.
已经在候命了
Already standing by.
报告，长官，传感器显示立方体是实心的
Reporting, sir. Sensors showed as solid,
但成分不明
but its composition is unknown to us.
- 乌乎拉上尉 - 呼叫频率仍然打开，长官
- Lieutenant Uhura. - Hailing frequency still open, sir.
我没收到它的任何反馈
I get no message from it.
领航员
Navigation.
距离我舰1593米，相对位置保持不变
Distance from us, 1,593 meters. Position constant.
各边边长107米
Each of its edges measures 107 meters.
质量小于1万1千吨
Mass, a little under 11,000 metric tons.
史考特
Scotty.
动力模式？我真搞不懂是什么让它运行的
Mode of power? Beats me what makes it go.
- 我可以接受一些推断 - 如果有推断我会说的
- I'll buy speculation. - I'd sell it if I had any.
那是一个实心立方体
That's a solid cube.
它是怎么感应到我们的？
How something like that can sense us coming,
堵住我们，我们动它也跟着动，真搞不懂
block us, move when we move, it beats me.
那就是我的报告
That's my report.
- 生命科学？ - 同样的报告
- Life sciences? - Same report.
长官，我们就这样让它堵着？
Sir, we gonna just let it hold us here?
我们有相位炮，我建议击毁它
We've got phaser weapons. I vote we blast it.
我会考虑一下的，贝利先生…
I'll keep that in mind, Mr. Bailey...
不过要等这里实行民主制的时候
...when this becomes a democracy.
舰长日志，星历1513.8
Captain's log, stardate 1513.8:
星图显示附近没有任何可居类行星
Star maps reveal no indication of habitable planets nearby.
立方体的来源和目的仍然不明
Origin and purpose of the cube still unknown.
我们在这里呆了18个小时，仍然没有任何头绪
We've been here, held motionless, for 18 hours.
- 各位还有何想法？ - 我认为
- Anything further, gentlemen? - I believe it adds up
有以下两种可能
to either one of two possibilities.
首先，可能是某种空间浮标
First, a space buoy of some kind.
第二呢？
Second?
捕蝇纸
Flypaper.
所以你建议别沾上它
And you don't recommend sticking around.
对，那会让我们显得相当被动
Negative. It would make us appear too weak.
是时候采取行动了，绅士们
It's time for action, gentlemen.
- 贝利先生… - 舰桥呼叫相位炮组
- Mr. Bailey... - Bridge to phaser-gun crew.
取消指令
Countermand.
- 怎么行动我自有打算… - 对不起，长官，我以为…
- I'll select what kind of action... - I'm sorry, sir. I thought...
贝利先生，你在解释吗？我没要你解释
Are you explaining, Mr. Bailey? I haven't requested an explanation.
现在我要说的是，领航员
Now as I was about to say, navigator,
给我们设定离开立方体的螺旋航线
plot us a spiral course away from the cube.
- 是，长官 - 我们会尽力从它旁边绕过
- Yes, sir. - We'll try pulling away from it.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
舵手呼叫轮机室，请侯命
Helmsman to engine room. Stand by.
所有甲板警戒状态，我们要尝试离开
All decks: Alert. We're gonna try pulling away.
航线设定完成并已经上路了，长官
Course plotted and laid in, sir.
开始，苏鲁先生，四分之一速度
Engage, Mr. Sulu. Quarter speed.
0.25，长官
Point-two-five, sir.
- 还是挡着我们，长官 - 我们看看它是否会让路
- Still blocking us, sir. - Let's see if it'll give way.
继续向前，半速
Ahead, half speed.
0.50，长官
Point-five-oh, sir.
来自光谱的短波端辐射正在增加
Radiation from the short end of the spectrum increasing.
所有引擎暂停，位置保持不变
All stop, hold position.
还在向我们飞来，距离190米
It's still coming toward us. Range, 190 meters.
- 辐射增强 - 动力倒车，半速
- Radiation increasing. - Power astern, half speed.
半速
Half speed.
- 辐射接近承受极限 - 还在过来，跑的比我们快
- Radiation nearing the tolerance level. - Still coming. Gaining on us.
引擎倒车，全速
Engines astern, full speed.
全速
Full speed.
现在距离是125米
Range, 125 meters now.
舵手，进入曲速
Helm, give us warp speed.
- 曲速1，长官 - 辐射在可承受临界边缘
- Warp 1, sir. - Radiation at the tolerance level.
曲速2，长官
Warp 2, sir.
现在是曲速3
Speed is now warp 3.
辐射超过极限，进入致命区
Radiation passing the tolerance level, entering lethal zone.
距离51米，还在接近，长官
Range, 51 meters and still closing, sir.
相位炮组，准备侯命
Phaser crew, stand ready.
相位炮组报告已经预备，长官
Phaser crew reports ready, sir.
辐射增长中，我们只能再坚持几秒了
Growing, we can take only a few more seconds of this.
相位炮锁定目标
Lock phasers on target.
贝利先生，锁定相位炮
Mr. Bailey, lock phasers.
相位炮锁定目标，长官
Phasers locked. On target, sir.
- 进入射程，还在接近中 - 主相位炮发射
- Point-blank range and closing. - Fire main phasers.
舰长日志，星历1514.0
Captain's log, stardate 1514.0:
立方体已被消灭，星舰损伤：轻微
The cube has been destroyed. Ship's damage, minor.
但我要决定，继续向前探测还是返回？
But my next decision, major. Probe on ahead or turn back?
什么都没有，舰长，看不到，各方向都没有物体
Nothing, captain. No contacts, no objects in any direction.
敢不敢推测一下继续前行会遇到什么吗？
Care to speculate on what we'll find if we go on ahead?
推测？
Speculate?
无法推测
No.
逻辑上，我们将会找到发送立方体的智能来源
Logically, we'll discover the intelligence which sent out the cube.
智能来源和我们不同，还是比我们高级？
Intelligence different from ours or superior?
都有可能
Probably both.
如果你需要逻辑判定…
And if you're asking the logical decision to make...
不，我没有
No, I'm not.
进取号的任务就是要探索和联系外星生命
The mission of the Enterprise is to seek out and contact alien life.
你不觉得对已经想好的事情…
Has it occurred to you that there's a certain...
还要不断来问我
...inefficiency in constantly questioning me
其实没什么意义吗？
on things you've already made up your mind about?
那样能让我有心理安慰
It gives me emotional security.
领航员，设定前行的航线
Navigator, set a course ahead.
绘制完毕、已经输入，长官
Plotted. Laid in, sir.
- 出发 - 曲速1，长官
- Engage. - Warp 1, sir.
贝利先生，相位炮组行动缓慢
Mr. Bailey, phaser crews were sluggish.
你在锁定时太慢了
You were slow in locking them into your directional beam.
舵手，轮机甲板也应该更快一些
Helmsman, engineering decks could have been faster too.
设定一系列的模拟攻击和躲避的机动演习
Program a series of simulated attacks and evasion maneuvers.
重复练习直至熟练，绅士们
Keep repeating the exercise until we're proficient, gentlemen.
- 是，长官 - 是，长官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
你来的真不是时候，吉姆
Your timing is lousy, Jim.
- 人们都累了 - 舰长室
- The men are tired. - Captain's quarters.
你不是总说受点苦可以增强意志吗？
Aren't you the one that always says a little suffering is good for the soul?
- 我从来没说过 - 这里是舰桥
- I never say that. - This is the Bridge.
准备模拟进攻
Prepare for simulated attack.
我尤其担心贝利
I'm especially worried about Bailey.
领航员的职务对一个老练的人都很难…
Navigator's position's rough enough for a seasoned man...
我想他能做好
I think he'll cut it.
这么肯定？他身上某个特质吸引了你？
How so sure? Because you spotted something you liked in him?
很熟悉吧？就像你年轻的时候，哦，大概11年前？
Something familiar? Like yourself, say about, oh, 11 years ago?
两倍速度，5层甲板，给我绿灯
On the double, deck five. Give me a green light.
怎么了，医生，你又在回忆了吗？
Why, doctor, you've been reading your textbooks again?
我不用回忆就知道你会把他提升的太快
I don't need textbooks to know that you could've promoted him too fast.
- 听听意见吧 - 警戒状态
- Listen to that voice. - Condition alert.
进入战斗岗位
Battle stations.
轮机室，5号甲板，报告
Engineering, deck five, report.
相位炮组，继续，我们开始
Phaser crews, come on, let's get with it.
二号相位炮台
Phaser station two,
- 还没准备好吗？ - 谢谢
- where's your green light? - Thank you.
你还想说什么？
What's next?
- 他们不是机器，吉姆 - 哦，他们不是
- "They're not machines, Jim?" - Well, they're not.
- 在他们经过考验后 - 麦考伊医生
- After what they've been through... - Dr. McCoy,
我听你说过人总比
I've heard you say that man is ultimately superior
- 任何机械设备都高级的 - 没有，我从没说过
- to any mechanical device. - No, I never say that either.
我发誓我听你说过
I could've sworn I heard you say that.
- 我是寇克 - 舰长，训练强度为94%
- Kirk here. - Exercise rating, captain, 94 percent.
- 史波克，强度增至100% - 好的
- Let's try for 100, Mr. Spock. - Agreed.
你打算拿这6%做什么，吉姆？
What are you gonna do with that six percent when they give it to you, Jim?
我会充分利用，我会…
I'm gonna take it, and I'm gonna...
打扰了，长官，餐点过了你还没吃饭呢
Excuse me, sir. It's past time you had something to eat.
这是什么鬼东西？菜叶子吗？
What the devil is this? Green leaves?
长官，这是食谱上的沙拉
It's dietary salad, sir.
麦考伊医生改善了您的膳食搭配，我以为您早知道了
Dr. McCoy ordered your diet card changed. I thought you knew.
你胖了几磅，忘记啦？
Your weight was up a couple of pounds, remember?
文书，你能别一直在我眼前晃吗？
Will you stop hovering over me, yeoman?
长官，您若不喜欢，给您换成别的
Well, I'll change it if you don't like it, sir.
- 给医生也来一盘 - 不要
- Bring some for the doctor too. - No, no.
船员吃完我才能吃
No, I never eat until the crew eats.
- 谢谢你，文书 - 长官，不客气
- Thank you, yeoman. - You're welcome, sir.
这里是舰桥
This is the Bridge.
所有甲板做好准备，接受第二次模拟演习
All decks prepare to better reaction time on second simulated attack.
当我发现那些总部的天才
When I get my hands on the headquarters genius
分配给我一位女性的文书时…
that assigned me a female yeoman...
怎么了，吉姆？你怎么不信任自己了？
What's the matter, Jim, don't you trust yourself?
进入战斗岗位
Battle stations.
轮机甲板警戒…
Engineering decks: Alert...
我身边已有个女人让我寝食难安了，她叫进取号
I've already got a female to worry about. Her name's the Enterprise.
轮机甲板警戒，相位炮手，请…
Engineering decks: Alert. Phaser crews, let's...
取消之前的命令，所有甲板进入战斗岗位
Countermand that. All decks to battle stations.
这不是演习，再说一遍，这不是演习
This is not a drill. Repeat, this is not a drill.
- 我是寇克 - 长官，我们遇到不明物体
- Kirk here. - We're picking up an object, sir.
- 体积更大，正朝我方行进 - 马上到
- Much larger, coming toward us. - Coming.
异常强烈的讯号
Exceptionally strong contact.
暂无影像数据
Not visual yet.
远程光谱成像表明
Distant spectrograph.
金属质地，与之前的立方体相似，能量读数值更大
Metallic, similar to cube. Much greater energy reading.
在那里，长官
There, sir.
速度减半，规避动作准备
Half speed. Prepare for evasive action.
长官，减至曲速2
Reducing to warp 2, sir.
长官，是牵引光束，我们被困住了
Tractor beam, captain. Something's grabbed us, hard.
- 长官，引擎正在过载 - 停止所有引擎
- Engines overloading, sir. - All engines stop.
长官，所有引擎已停止
All engines stopped, sir.
- 相位炮手待命 - 舰桥呼叫相位炮手，待命
- Phaser crews, stand ready. - Bridge to phaser crew, stand ready.
前向相位炮手听命
Forward phaser, will comply.
所有武器操作就绪
All weapons at operational ready.
超乎想象
Fascinating.
史波克，物体质量是多少？
What's its mass, Mr. Spock?
舰长，读数超出可测量范围，直径得有1英里
The reading goes off my scale, captain. It must be a mile in diameter.
距离5千多米了，还看不见全景
Over 5,000 meters away and it still fills the screen.
缩小视图，我要看全景图
Reduce image. Let me see all of it.
长官，倍率25
Magnification 25, sir.
长官，倍率18.5
Magnification 18.5, sir.
舰船通话
Ship to ship.
长官，呼叫频率已开启
Hailing frequencies open, sir.
这里是联邦星舰进取号
This is the United Earth ship Enterprise.
我们传达问候，等待你们的回复
We convey greetings and await your reply.
- 贝利，听见什么了？ - 一条信息
- What is it, Mr. Bailey? - A message.
通过导航光束传过来的
Coming over my navigation beam.
- 接受信息 - 长官，正在转换
- Pick it up. - Switching, sir.
…并且侵入我们的星系
- And trespassed into our star systems.
我是巴洛
This is Balok,
第一联邦旗舰费赛睿思号的指挥官
commander of the flagship Fesarius of the First Federation.
进取号显然是野蛮原始社会的产物
Your vessel, obviously the product of a primitive and savage civilization,
你们先无视而后摧毁了我们的警告浮标
having ignored a warning buoy and having then destroyed it,
此种行为早已明示了敌意
has demonstrated your intention is not peaceful.
我们正在考虑进取号
We are now considering the disposition of your ship
及其船员的处置事宜
and the life aboard.
- 舰船通话 - 呼叫频率已开启，长官
- Ship to ship. - Hailing frequencies open, sir.
我是进取号舰长
This is the captain of the Enterprise speaking.
我们并不知晓空间浮标的警示含义
The warning nature of your space buoy was unknown to us.
浮标挡住了去路，当我们想办法离开时…
Our vessel was blocked, and when we attempted to disengage...
舰长，异常强烈的探测信号
Captain, we're being invaded
正入侵舰船各个系统
by exceptionally strong senso-probes everywhere.
电力系统，引擎…
Our electrical systems, our engines...
一切协商概不接受
No further communication will be accepted.
倘若再有一丝敌意行动
If there is the slightest hostile move,
我们将立即摧毁进取号
your vessel will be destroyed immediately.
舰长，他们强制关闭了我们的某些系统
They're shutting off some of our systems, captain.
太有才了
Brilliant.
手法非常先进
Extremely sophisticated in their methods.
记录信标的磁带记录了相关信息吗？
Does our recorder marker have all this on its tapes?
- 记录足以警示其他的地球舰船了 - 贝利，发射记录信标
- Enough to warn other Earth ships. - Mr. Bailey, dispatch recorder marker.
贝利？
Mr. Bailey?
长官，信标已发射
Recorder marker dispatched, sir.
信标在航线上，向着我们来时的方向…
Marker on course. Heading back the way we...
你们的记录信标已被摧毁
Your recorder marker has been destroyed.
你们已被检查完毕
You have been examined.
进取号必须被摧毁
Your ship must be destroyed.
我们发现你们信奉神明，心怀信念
We make assumption you have a deity or deities
为了缓解不安情绪
or some such beliefs which comfort you.
我们给予你们10分钟的地球时间
We therefore grant you ten Earth time periods known as minutes
准备接受毁灭
to make preparations.
如果能定位发声地
Might be interesting to see what they look like if I can locate
我倒想看看他们究竟是何方神圣
where that voice is coming from.
大家都知道巴洛的口信了
Balok's message, it was heard all over the ship.
舰员请注意，我是舰长，各位在进取号上服役已久
Captain to crew. Those of you who have served for long on this vessel
也曾遭遇过外星生命
have encountered alien life forms.
你们知道我们面对的最大威胁是自身
You know the greatest danger facing us is ourselves,
和对未知事物不理智的恐惧，但未知之事并不可怕
an irrational fear of the unknown. But there's no such thing as the unknown.
它们只是暂时不解之事，暂时不明之物
Only things temporarily hidden, temporarily not understood.
在大多数情况下，我们认为有能力创造文明的高等生物
In most cases, we have found that intelligence capable of a civilization
同时也具备理解友好行为的能力
is capable of understanding peaceful gestures.
我确信能够进行空间旅行的物种
Surely a life form advanced enough for space travel
终会理解我们行为的意义
is advanced enough to eventually understand our motives.
所有甲板待命
All decks, stand by.
舰长完毕
Captain out.
- 舰船通话 - 呼叫频率已开启，长官
- Ship to ship. - Hailing frequencies open, sir.
我是联邦星舰进取号的舰长
This is the captain of the USS Enterprise.
我们到来是为寻找友谊，并非有意冒犯
We came seeking friendship, but we have no wish to trespass.
我们将原路返回以示友好
To demonstrate our goodwill, our vessel will now return the way it came.
我们…
We...
贝利，预先输入一条航线
Lay in a course ahead, Mr. Bailey.
什么？
What?
航线？
A course?
- 绘制并且输入，长官 - 开始，曲速1
- Plotted and laid in, sir. - Engage, warp factor 1.
曲速系数
Warp factor.
没有反应
There's no response.
切换到脉冲引擎
Switch to impulse.
引擎与武器设备已全部瘫痪
All engine systems show dead, and weapon systems.
开启屏显，我能搞到些影像资料
Switching to screen. I believe I can get something visual.
你们在做无用功
You are wasting time and effort.
你们无路可逃
There is no escape.
距离毁灭还剩8分钟
You have eight Earth minutes left.
之前我很好奇他们长啥样
I was curious to see how they appeared.
当然，这很正常
Yes, of course you were.
我真搞不懂
I don't understand this.
史波克在浪费时间
Spock's wasting time.
大家完全在坐以待毙
Everybody else just sitting around.
- 总得行动起来 - 冷静，贝利
- Somebody's got to do something. - Easy, Bailey.
他们到底想要什么？我们搞清楚他们想要什么…
What do they want from us? Let's find out what they want...
- 他们想要我们的命 - 只剩8分钟了
- They want us to lose our heads... - We've only got eight minutes left.
是7分41秒
Seven minutes and 41 seconds.
看见没，他还做倒数读秒呢
See, he's doing a countdown!
- 只是看看警戒啥时候结束 - 你们都疯了不成？
- Practically end of watch. - What, are you all out of your minds?
警戒结束？
End of watch?
那时一切都完了，你们是机器人吗？
It's the end of everything. What are you, robots?
上足发条的玩具兵吗？你们不知道自己快死了吗？
Wound-up toy soldiers? Don't you know when you're dying?
警戒，规矩还有命令，都他妈的是什么东西？
Watch and regulations and orders, what do they mean?
贝利，你被解除职务了
Bailey, you're relieved!
医生，护送他回舱房
Escort him to his quarters, doctor.
我们走
Let's go.
- 舰船通话 - 呼叫频率已开启，长官
- Ship to ship. - Hailing frequencies open, sir.
我是进取号舰长
This is the captain of the Enterprise speaking.
如若可能，地球人习惯避免并解除误会
It is the custom of Earth people to try and avoid misunderstanding
我们摧毁了你们的空间浮标
whenever possible. We destroyed your space buoy
仅为自保
as a simple act of self-preservation.
当我们想方设法避开它时
When we attempted to move away from it,
它发出了对人体有害的辐射
it emitted radiation harmful to our species.
如果你检查过进取号和船上的卡带
If you've examined our ship and its tapes,
你定然知道我说的句句属实
you know this to be true.
还剩7分钟
You now have seven minutes left.
还剩4分30秒
Four minutes, 30 seconds.
苏鲁，你就那么喜欢倒计时？
You have an annoying fascination for timepieces, Mr. Sulu.
吉姆
Jim.
还剩4分钟
Four minutes.
他们到底怎么啦？
What's the matter with them out there?
他们肯定知道我们没歹心
They must know we mean them no harm.
现在他们肯定知道我们完全没资本起歹心
They're certainly aware by now that we're totally incapable of it.
一定有解决办法
There must be something to do.
一些我忽略的事情
Something I've overlooked.
下棋的时候
In chess,
赢家的诞生意味着游戏结束
when one is outmatched, the game is over.
将死
Checkmate.
这就是你最好的建议？
Is that your best recommendation?
我…
I'm...
抱歉我没能找到其他合乎逻辑的建议
I regret that I can find no other logical alternative.
- 假定我们脱离… - 还没人放弃
- Assuming we get out of this... - Nobody's given up yet.
那么，谈谈贝利
Well, then, about Bailey.
要不就在医疗诊断记录里写成疲劳过度吧
Let me enter it in my medical records as simple fatigue.
- 写什么我来决定，医生 - 这是你的错
- That's my decision, doctor. - And it was your mistake.
你让他加班，逼他，对他期望值过高
You overworked him, pushed him, expected too much out of him.
我命令你闭嘴
I'm ordering you to drop it.
我没时间听你的思想理论
I've no time for you, your theories, your quaint philosophies.
我要挑战你在医疗记录上的干涉
I intend to challenge your actions in my medical records.
我会写上我曾警告过你贝利的状态不佳
I'll state that I warned you about Bailey's condition.
- 这不是吓唬 - 任何时候你都可以吓唬我，医生…
- Now, that's no bluff. - Any time you can bluff me, doctor...
还剩3分钟
Three minutes.
好的，医生，但愿还有时间讨论这个
All right, doctor. Let's hope we have time to argue about it.
史波克，象棋不太贴切
Not chess, Mr. Spock.
扑克牌更适合
Poker.
你会打牌吗？
Do you know the game?
- 舰船通话 - 呼叫频率已开启，长官
- Ship to ship. - Hailing frequencies open, sir.
我是进取号舰长
This is the captain of the Enterprise.
出于对其他物种的尊重，我将给予你以下警告
Our respect for other life forms requires that we give you this warning.
有这样一条重要的信息从未被输入
One critical item of information that has never been incorporated
任何一艘地球舰船的记忆库
into the memory banks of any Earth ship.
自早年的空间探索开始
Since the early years of space exploration,
地球舰船上便混合了
Earth vessels have had incorporated into them
一种名为“科波麦特”的物质
a substance known as corbomite.
它是一种材料和装置使得我们免受攻击
It is a material and a device which prevents attack on us.
一旦有毁灭性能量接触舰体
If any destructive energy touches our vessel,
便会产生一股等量且反方向的力量，摧毁…
a reverse reaction of equal strength is created, destroying...
还剩两分钟
You now have two minutes.
摧毁攻击者
Destroying the attacker.
也许你有兴趣了解一下
It may interest you to know
自首次使用科波麦特以来
that since the initial use of corbomite
200多年过去了
more than two of our centuries ago,
任何攻击的飞船都无一幸免
no attacking vessel has survived the attempt.
生死对人类来说不过常态
Death has little meaning to us.
倘若对你也是如此…
If it has none to you...
请动手吧
...then attack us now.
对你的愚蠢我们已忍无可忍了
We grow annoyed at your foolishness.
不管怎样，一张好牌
However, it was well played.
真后悔没能好好了解一下巴洛
I regret not having learned more about this Balok.
他多多少少让我想起了我父亲
In some manner, he was reminiscent of my father.
愿上天帮助你的母亲
Then may heaven have helped your mother.
恰恰相反
Quite the contrary.
我母亲觉得自己是个幸运的地球女人
She considered herself a very fortunate Earth woman.
医生，对不起
Doc. Sorry.
是我的错，你当时在考虑别的事情
For having other things on your mind? My fault.
我不知道你怎样克制不用拳头痛击我的脸
I don't know how in the devil you kept from punching me in the face.
一分钟
One minute.
我知道他会的
I knew he would.
如果还有人想知道的话，30秒
If anyone's interested, 30 seconds.
请求回到岗位，长官
Request permission to return to post, sir.
批准
Permission granted.
倒数11秒
Eleven.
Ten seconds.
9、8
Nine, eight,
7、6
seven, six,
5、4
five, four,
3、2、1
three, two, one.
很有趣的游戏，这种扑克游戏
A very interesting game, this poker.
这的确比象棋更好
It does have advantages over chess.
我很愿意教你
Love to teach it to you.
这是费赛睿思号的指挥官
This is the commander of the Fesarius.
来了，是增加筹码还是摊牌？
Here it comes. Is it raise or call?
对你们飞船的摧毁行动被延时了
The destruction of your vessel has been delayed.
我们要证实你们飞船上有科波麦特装置
We will relent in your destruction
才会放过你们的飞船
only if we have proof of your corbomite device.
稳住
Hold on that.
让他去想怎么办
Let him sweat for a change.
- 舰船通话 - 呼叫频率，长官
- Ship to ship. - Hailing frequency, sir.
拒绝要求
Request denied.
我收到影像联络，舰长
I have visual contact, captain.
我们会很快告知你们
We will soon inform you of our decision
关于你们的飞船的处理决定
regarding your vessel.
我已经让你们看了我的生命形态
And having permitted your primitive efforts to see my form,
我相信这已经满足了你们的好奇心
I trust it has pleased your curiosity.
现在
And now,
作为我们是优等生物的另一个证明
another demonstration of our superiority.
我以为厨房没有了能源
I thought the power was off in the galley.
我使用了一只相位手枪，热咖啡就出来了
I used a hand phaser, and zap, hot coffee.
有情况，舰长
Something's going on, captain.
- 一艘小型飞船 - 大约2000吨
- It's a small ship. - About 2,000 metric tons.
我们已经决定
It has been decided
把你们带到第一联盟的一个星球上
that I will conduct you to a planet of the First Federation
那里的环境可以维持你们的生命
which is capable of sustaining your life form.
你们会被带下船，关押起来
There, you will disembark and be interned.
当然，你们的飞船会被摧毁
Your ship will be destroyed, of course.
舰长，引擎系统恢复了
Engine systems coming on, captain.
不要觉得这艘领航船很小
Do not be deceived by the size of this pilot vessel.
它也有摧毁你们飞船的能力
It has an equal potential to destroy your vessel.
牵引光束又启动了
Tractor beam again.
为了让你们维持重力和大气系统
So that you may sustain your gravity and atmosphere,
你们的系统现在可以用了
your systems are now open.
但是逃跑是不可能的
Escape is impossible
因为你们将被我们的动力拉去目的地
since you are being taken under our power to your destination.
如果有任何逃跑或者摧毁这艘飞船的举动
Any move to escape or destroy this ship
我们都会马上摧毁进取号
will result in the instant destruction of the Enterprise
以及船上的所有人
and everyone aboard.
我们在被牵引，长官
We're being towed, sir.
舰长日记，星历 1514.1
Captain's log, stardate 1514.1:
进取号正被牵制
The Enterprise is in tow.
目前，我们还没有做任何抵抗
To this point, no resistance has been offered.
我的计划是假装顺从
My plan, a show of resignation.
巴洛的牵引系统肯定会消耗这艘小飞船的大量能量
Balok's tractor beam has to be a heavy drain of power on a small ship.
问题是，他会不会掉以轻心？
Question, will he grow careless?
舰长，他稍微离我们远了一点点
Captain, he's pulling out a little ahead of us.
他偷偷减小了一些动力
He's sneaked power down a bit.
我们的速度降到0.64倍光速
Our speed is down to 0.64 of light.
找一条直角的航线，跟他分离开
I want a right-angle course. Shear away from him,
- 不管往哪个方向飞都一样 - 好的，长官
- no matter which way he turns. - Yes, sir.
我一下令，就加速到最大
Maximum acceleration when I give the word.
好的，长官
Yes, sir.
开始
Engage.
拉力很大，舰长，引擎正在过载
It's a strain, captain. Engines are overloading.
- 加大动力 - 引擎过热
- More power. - We're super-heating.
混合温度7400度
Intermix temperature, 7,400 degrees.
7500度
Seven-five.
7600度
Seven-six.
8000度
Eight thousand degrees.
就现在，贝利！
Shear away, Mr. Bailey!
高出上限2000度了
Two thousand degrees above maximum.
8400度
Eight-four.
8500度
Eight-five.
8600度
Eight-six.
- 很快就会爆炸的！ - 现在，苏鲁，加上脉冲动力
- She'll blow soon! - Now, Mr. Sulu. Impulse power too.
我们挣脱了，长官
We're breaking free, sir.
停止所有引擎
All engines, stop.
所有引擎停止了，长官
All engines stopped, sir.
我们急需去维修引擎，舰长
Engines need work badly, captain.
- 能在这里停几个小时吗？ - 那可能不太妙
- Can you hold it here a few hours? - That may not be wise.
如果他给母舰发个信号…
If he got a signal through to the mothership...
我们还没有安全
Then we're not home yet.
有信号，舰长
A signal, captain.
很微弱，是巴洛
It's very weak. It's Balok.
是向费赛睿思号发送的求救信号
It's a distress signal to the Fesarius.
他的引擎无法启动了
His engines are out.
他的生命维持系统不工作了
His life-sustaining system isn't operating.
- 信息在重复发送，长官 - 有回复吗？
- The message is repeating, sir. - Any reply?
没有，他的信号越来越弱了
Negative. His signal is growing weak.
长官，我觉得母舰不会收到这信号了
Sir, I doubt if the mothership could've heard it.
准备去它那的航线，贝利
Plot a course for it, Mr. Bailey.
去营救它，舰长？
For it, captain?
必须去
Dead ahead.
我是舰长
This is the captain speaking.
第一联盟的飞船在危难中，我们准备去营救它
The First Federation vessel is in distress. We're preparing to board it.
有生命需要援救，虽然是外星生命
There are lives at stake. By our standards, alien life.
但也是生命，完毕
But lives nevertheless. Captain out.
航线绘制完毕并输入，长官
Course plotted and laid in, sir.
史考特，准备传送
Mr. Scott, ready the transporter room.
好的，长官
Aye, sir.
苏鲁，靠近到100米内，慢速靠近
Mr. Sulu, bring us to within 100 meters. Ahead slow.
慢速靠近，长官
Ahead slow, sir.
- 吉姆，你不觉得… - 这艘飞船的…
- Jim, don't you think..? - What's the mission
任务是什么，医生？
of this vessel, doctor?
寻找并接触外星生命
To seek out and contact alien life.
这是一个证明我们宣言的机会
And an opportunity to demonstrate what our high-sounding words mean.
还有问题吗？
Any questions?
我会带2个人一起
I'll take two men with me.
麦考伊医生，如有必要，去检查救助外星人
Dr. McCoy, to examine and treat the aliens if necessary,
还有你，贝利
and you, Mr. Bailey.
- 长官？ - 而对未知的
- Sir? - The face of the unknown.
我觉得我欠你看它一眼
I think I owe you a look at it.
好的，长官
Yes, sir.
- 舰长，请求允许到… - 拒绝
- Captain, request permission to... - Denied.
如果我判断失误，如果这是陷阱，我需要你在这里
If I'm wrong, if it's a trap, I want you here.
- 传送器准备好了吗？ - 是的，长官，但是有风险
- Transporter ready? - Well, yes, sir. But it's risky.
我们已经锁定了一个看起来像主甲板的地方
We're locked in on what appears to be a main deck.
- 空气成分？ - 可以呼吸
- Air sample? - Breathable.
事实上，比我们这里的氧气含量还高点
In fact, a slightly higher oxygen content than our own.
- 通讯器 - 好的
- Communicator. - Good.
- 相位武器 - 谢谢你，史考特，准备好了吗，医生？
- Phaser weapon. - Thank you, Scotty. Ready, doctor?
没有，但什么都阻止不了你了
No, but you won't let that stop you.
弯下身子，先生们
Bend low, gentlemen.
读数显示那里的空间很狭小
It reads pretty cramped over there.
- 准备传送 - 开始
- Ready to transport. - Energize.
这是个假人
It's a dummy.
一种木偶
A puppet of some kind.
我是巴洛，欢迎上船
I'm Balok. Welcome aboard.
- 我是寇克舰长 - 还有麦考伊和贝利
- I'm Captain Kirk. - And McCoy and Bailey.
坐，别客气
Sit. Be comfortable.
不要客气，坐吧
Go ahead, be seated.
喝点什么
We must drink.
这是氚雅
This is tranya.
我希望你们也喜欢它的味道
I hope you relish it as much as I.
巴洛指挥官…
Commander Balok...
我知道，知道，你有很多问题
I know, I know. A thousand questions.
但是，先喝氚雅
But first, the tranya.
先生们
Gentlemen.
指挥官，那个木偶…
Commander, that puppet...
另一个我，可以这么说
My alter ego, so to speak.
他相当于你们文化中的坏人
In your culture, he would be Mr. Hyde to my Jekyll.
你必须承认，他很有效
You must admit, he's effective.
你是不会被我的样子吓到的
You would never have been frightened by me.
我觉得我的求救信号很聪明
And I thought my distress signal quite clever.
这都是为了测试你们
It was a pleasure testing you.
测试我们？
Testing us?
我明白了
I see.
我必须要弄清楚你们的真实目的
I had to discover your real intentions.
但是你探测了我们的记忆数据库
But you probed our memory banks.
那些记录也可能是你们的陷阱
Your records could have been a deception on your part.
那你的船员呢？
And your crew?
我没有船员，医生，我控制一切
I have no crew, doctor. I run everything.
从这艘小船里面控制整个复合体
This entire complex from this small ship.
但是我也想要有人陪伴，可以对话
But I miss company, conversation.
就算是外星人也欢迎
Even an alien would be welcome.
也许你可能留下一个人陪我一段时间
Perhaps one of your men for some period of time.
进行信息和文化交流
An exchange of information, cultures.
是的，我们肯定都会受益
Yes, both our cultures would benefit.
你知道我们在哪可以找到自愿者吗，贝利？
Do you know where we can find a volunteer, Mr. Bailey?
我，长官，我愿意
Me, sir. I'd like to volunteer.
你代表了地球的最高水平？
You represent Earth's best then?
不，先生，我不能，我常犯错
No, sir, I'm not. I'll make plenty of mistakes.
但是你会通过这些了解我们更多
But you'd find out more about us that way.
作为回报，我会得到一个更好的军官
And I'd get a better officer in return.
明白了
I see.
我们思维差不多，舰长，你和我
We think much alike, captain, you and I.
现在，在我召回费赛睿思号前
Now, before I bring back the Fesarius,
让我带你看看我的飞船
let me show you my vessel.
这种机会不常有哦
It is not often I have this pleasure.
是的，我们很像，舰长
Yes, we're very much alike, captain.
都为自己的飞船而自豪
Both proud of our ships.
本集结束
-=The Last Fantasy=-
谢谢观赏